{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following type of class allows only one object of it to be created?", "opta": "Virtual class", "optb": "Abstract class", "optc": "Singleton class", "optd": "Friend class", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a type of constructor?", "opta": "Copy constructor", "optb": "Friend constructor", "optc": "Default constructor", "optd": "Parameterized constructor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct?", "opta": "Base class pointer cannot point to derived class.", "optb": "Derived class pointer cannot point to base class.", "optc": "Pointer to derived class cannot be created.", "optd": "Pointer to base class cannot be created.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not the member of class?", "opta": "Static function", "optb": "Friend function", "optc": "Const function", "optd": "Virtual function", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts means determining at runtime what method to invoke?", "opta": "Data hiding", "optb": "Dynamic Typing", "optc": "Dynamic binding", "optd": "Dynamic loading", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following term is used for a function defined inside a class?", "opta": "Member Variable", "optb": "Member function", "optc": "Class function", "optd": "Classic function", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concept of oops allows compiler to insert arguments in a function call if it is not specified?", "opta": "Call by value", "optb": "Call by reference", "optc": "Default arguments", "optd": "Call by pointer", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many instances of an abstract class can be created?", "opta": "1", "optb": "5", "optc": "13", "optd": "0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following cannot be friend?", "opta": "Function", "optb": "Class", "optc": "Object", "optd": "Operator function", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts of OOPS means exposing only necessary information to client?", "opta": "Encapsulation", "optb": "Abstraction", "optc": "Data hiding", "optd": "Data binding", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why reference is not same as a pointer?", "opta": "A reference can never be null.", "optb": "A reference once established cannot be changed.", "optc": "Reference doesn't need an explicit dereferencing mechanism.", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "cout is a/an __________ .", "opta": "operator", "optb": "function", "optc": "object", "optd": "macro", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts provides facility of using object of one class inside another class?", "opta": "Encapsulation", "optb": "Abstraction", "optc": "Composition", "optd": "Inheritance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many types of polymorphisms are supported by C++?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The two main types of polymorphism are run-time (implemented as inheritance and virtual functions), and compile-time (implemented as templates)."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an abstract data type?", "opta": "int", "optb": "double", "optc": "string", "optd": "Class", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts means adding new components to a program as it runs?", "opta": "Data hiding", "optb": "Dynamic typing", "optc": "Dynamic binding", "optd": "Dynamic loading", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "A constructor is called at the time of declaration of an object.", "optb": "A constructor is called at the time of use of an object.", "optc": "A constructor is called at the time of declaration of a class.", "optd": "A constructor is called at the time of use of a class.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following correctly describes overloading of functions?", "opta": "Virtual polymorphism", "optb": "Transient polymorphism", "optc": "Ad-hoc polymorphism", "optd": "Pseudo polymorphism", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following approach is adapted by C++?", "opta": "Top-down", "optb": "Bottom-up", "optc": "Right-left", "optd": "Left-right", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct about function overloading?", "opta": "The types of arguments are different.", "optb": "The order of argument is different.", "optc": "The number of argument is same.", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct about class and structure?", "opta": "class can have member functions while structure cannot.", "optb": "class data members are public by default while that of structure are private.", "optc": "Pointer to structure or classes cannot be declared.", "optd": "class data members are private by default while that of structure are public by default.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts means wrapping up of data and functions together?", "opta": "Abstraction", "optb": "Encapsulation", "optc": "Inheritance", "optd": "Polymorphism", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts means waiting until runtime to determine which function to call?", "opta": "Data hiding", "optb": "Dynamic casting", "optc": "Dynamic binding", "optd": "Dynamic loading", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How \"Late binding\" is implemented in C++?", "opta": "Using C++ tables", "optb": "Using Virtual tables", "optc": "Using Indexed virtual tables", "optd": "Using polymorphic tables", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following operator is overloaded for object cout?", "opta": ">>", "optb": "<<", "optc": "+", "optd": "=", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the correct class of the object cout?", "opta": "iostream", "optb": "istream", "optc": "ostream", "optd": "ifstream", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following cannot be used with the keyword virtual?", "opta": "class", "optb": "member functions", "optc": "constructor", "optd": "destructor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following functions are performed by a constructor?", "opta": "Construct a new class", "optb": "Construct a new object", "optc": "Construct a new function", "optd": "Initialize objects", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following problem causes an exception?", "opta": "Missing semicolon in statement in main().", "optb": "A problem in calling function.", "optc": "A syntax error.", "optd": "A run-time error.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following options is correct about the statement given below? The compiler checks the type of reference in the object and not the type of object.", "opta": "Inheritance", "optb": "Polymorphism", "optc": "Abstraction", "optd": "Encapsulation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the correct way of declaring a function as constant?", "opta": "const int ShowData(void) { /* statements */ }", "optb": "int const ShowData(void) { /* statements */ }", "optc": "int ShowData(void) const { /* statements */ }", "optd": "Both A and B", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following concepts is used to implement late binding?", "opta": "Virtual function", "optb": "Operator function", "optc": "Const function", "optd": "Static function", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "C++ allows static type checking.", "optb": "C++ allows dynamic type checking.", "optc": "C++ allows static member function be of type const.", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following factors supports the statement that reusability is a desirable feature of a language?", "opta": "It decreases the testing time.", "optb": "It lowers the maintenance cost.", "optc": "It reduces the compilation time.", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following ways are legal to access a class data member using this pointer?", "opta": "this->x", "optb": "this.x", "optc": "*this.x", "optd": "*this-x", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a mechanism of static polymorphism?", "opta": "Operator overloading", "optb": "Function overloading", "optc": "Templates", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct about the statements given below?\n  All operators can be overloaded in C++.\n  We can change the basic meaning of an operator in C++.", "opta": "Only I is true.", "optb": "Both I and II are false.", "optc": "Only II is true.", "optd": "Both I and II are true.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens if the base and derived class contains definition of a function with same prototype?", "opta": "Compiler reports an error on compilation.", "optb": "Only base class function will get called irrespective of object.", "optc": "Only derived class function will get called irrespective of object.", "optd": "Base class object will call base class function and derived class object will call derived class function.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are available only in the class hierarchy chain?", "opta": "Public data members", "optb": "Private data members", "optc": "Protected data members", "optd": "Member functions", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a type of inheritance?", "opta": "Multiple", "optb": "Multilevel", "optc": "Distributive", "optd": "Hierarchical", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following operators cannot be overloaded?", "opta": "[]", "optb": "->", "optc": "?:", "optd": "*", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following a virtual call is resolved at the time of compilation?", "opta": "From inside the destructor.", "optb": "From inside the constructor.", "optc": "From inside the main().", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements regarding inline functions is correct?", "opta": "It speeds up execution.", "optb": "It slows down execution.", "optc": "It increases the code size.", "optd": "Both A and C.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is the correct way to declare a pure virtual function?", "opta": "virtual void Display(void){0};", "optb": "virtual void Display = 0;", "optc": "virtual void Display(void) = 0;", "optd": "void Display(void) = 0;", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following header file includes definition of cin and cout?", "opta": "istream.h", "optb": "ostream.h", "optc": "iomanip.h", "optd": "iostream.h", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following keyword is used to overload an operator?", "opta": "overload", "optb": "operator", "optc": "friend", "optd": "override", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What will happen if a class is not having any name?", "opta": "It cannot have a destructor.", "optb": "It cannot have a constructor.", "optc": "It is not allowed.", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which inheritance type is used in the class given below?  class A : public X, public Y {}", "opta": "Multilevel inheritance", "optb": "Multiple inheritance", "optc": "Hybrid inheritance", "optd": "Hierarchical Inheritance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is correct about the statements given below?\n  All function calls are resolved at compile-time in Procedure Oriented Programming.\n  All function calls are resolved at compile-time in OOPS.", "opta": "Only II is correct.", "optb": "Both I and II are correct.", "optc": "Only I is correct.", "optd": "Both I and II are incorrect.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an invalid visibility label while inheriting a class?", "opta": "public", "optb": "private", "optc": "protected", "optd": "friend", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following options is correct?", "opta": "Friend function can access public data members of the class.", "optb": "Friend function can access protected data members of the class.", "optc": "Friend function can access private data members of the class.", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct in C++?", "opta": "Classes cannot have data as protected members.", "optb": "Structures can have functions as members.", "optc": "Class members are public by default.", "optd": "Structure members are private by default.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used to make an abstract class?", "opta": "Declaring it abstract using static keyword.", "optb": "Declaring it abstract using virtual keyword.", "optc": "Making at least one member function as virtual function.", "optd": "Making at least one member function as pure virtual function.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following access specifier is used as a default in a class definition?", "opta": "protected", "optb": "public", "optc": "private", "optd": "friend", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is correct about the static data member of a class?", "opta": "A static member function can access only static data members of a class.", "optb": "A static data member is shared among all the object of the class.", "optc": "A static data member can be accessed directly from main().", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following provides a reuse mechanism?", "opta": "Abstraction", "optb": "Inheritance", "optc": "Dynamic binding", "optd": "Encapsulation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Class is an instance of object.", "optb": "Object is an instance of a class.", "optc": "Class is an instance of data type.", "optd": "Object is an instance of data type.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}